Stanislav Myakishev

https://stanislavmyakishev.github.io/

Programming Skills

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, jQuery, effector, GraphQL, cypress, vitest, react-router, Sass, styled-components

Summary

Throughout my 4-year-plus career as a software engineer, I have focused on developing products that provide the most value to businesses and help achieving their goals. I enjoy collaborative work but also able to run projects independently. My passion is a continuous learning, knowledge management and sharing which helps me to hire, onboard and edify colleagues.

EXPERIENCE

Go Travel Un Limited (Tickets metasearch with 20M monthly active users)

Hong Kong

Software engineer

Mar. 2022 - present

Email: masiff.s@gmail.com

Telegram: @smyakishev

Leading the development of the CMS/CRM travel content system frontend client, meeting the reqirements of editors and scouts, and ensuring its suitability for external use. Hired, onboarded and mentored frontend developers for the project needs.

- Designed, developed and migrated the CMS to the new React/TypeScript/Effector client, which increased the speed of content delivery by 20% and reduced the development costs for new parts of the product.
- Enhanced editor productivity by 40-50% and increased the stability of the legacy CMS client by implementing the webpack bundling, integrating reliable CSRF checks, and thoroughly covering core functionality with unit tests.
- Automated the procedure of sending and signing offers with content authors through the creation of a dedicated CRM application built with Node/React, which reduced the signing process time by 90%.

Sberbank (60th largest bank in the world)

Saint Petersburg, Russia

Jul. 2020 - Feb.2022

Senior Frontend Developer

React/TypeScript/GraphQL client of release orchestration tool for DevOps pipelines centralization. Application is used by 35% of bank apps (2700+ applications and services). Started as a junior developer and got three promotions after. In the last few months of work took the role of the product manager.

- Reduced the weight of the pipeline save request by 40% via developing a GraphQL mutation approach instead of a REST API, which reduced the running time of the main scenario by 30%.
- Designed and implemented e2e tests in the project from scratch, developed test cases covering the main functionality. This initiative led to a reduction in manual testing time, by 50-60%.
- Achieved a 30% reduction in routing bugs by upgrading the project from react-router 3.0 to 5.0. This involved a comprehensive renovation and transfer of routing scheme to the TypeScript, accompanied by new dev utilities.

Emphasoft

Saint Petersburg, Russia

Frontend developer

Oct. 2019 - Jul. 2020

Developed and refined the React applications for small/medium-sized businesses. Worked on AI interface of the electronic shopping cart platform (shopic.co and a real estate agency website (parkplacemi.com) .

- Built the interface of the redesigned products cart page, which introduced new features and increased the interface interaction speed by 20%.
- $\circ\,$ Implemented a main form for creating a property sale page (used by 100+ companies on launch)
- Engineered the core of corporate chat (React/Redux/Material UI). Developed corporate chat bots, making possible the company's full migration of communication to the internal platform.

EDUCATION

ITMO University

QS World University Rankings: Top 100 in CS; GPA: 4.8/5.0

BSc, Computer Science

Sep. 2017 – Jun. 2021

South-Eastern Finland University of Applied Sciences

Exchange study Jan. 2019 – May. 2019

GPA: 4.7/5.0

- CCNA Routing and Switching (Cisco learning lab)
- Microsoft Security Fundamentals course (University based)